

tl;dr_

Software engineer with 5 years of experience, fascination for intriguing computer science problems and a flair for Systems programming & Site Reliability. Believes in using the right tool for the right job. Finds home coding in Python and talking about Clojure.

Experience _____

SIGHUP Srl Milan, Italy

KUBERNETES ENGINEER May 2021 - Present

I help develop and maintain a battle tested Kubernetes Distribution called KFD, which is maintained completely open source and provides an easy way to setup, configure and manage Kubernetes clusters in large scale.

Quick Algorithm Srl Milan, Italy

TECH LEAD

April 2018 - April 2021

I help develop the scalable infrastructure for the data crunching algorithms that the company offer as a service. My job involves deploying and managing the infrastructure which includes our own data vizualization platform and several pipelines for.

Pears Remote

CORE DEVELOPER July 2016 - Present

PeARS is a free and open source, distributed, and lightweight search engine using distributional semantics technique. The project has been funded so far by the University of Cambridge and the Mozilla foundation. Develops critical components of the product.

Red Hat Inc.

Bangalore, India

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER (PYTHON, C)

January 2015 - June 2016

Worked as a member of the Gluster filesystem development team. Wrote features and tools both in C and Python to improve the performance and usability of the product.

Bang The Table Pvt. Ltd.

Bangalore, India

RUBY ON RAILS SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

May 2014 - Dec. 2014

Implemented many enhancement features like survey, pools, etc. to the community engagement platform EngagementHQ for Australian, New Zealand, and Canadian Govt. Worked with the customer support team to fix core product issues by meeting SLAs

Projects & Open Source Contributions ____

Tweefka - Developed a twitter like streaming web app, which uses Kafka as a message broker and	Developer
e e e e e e e e e e e e e e e e e e e	
	Core Developer
Wrote and maintained numerous Ansible modules for the upstream Ansible repository.	00.020.0000.
Automated Rendering Testing - As a part of the Google Summer of Code project, wrote a tool to	
test the rendering of fonts by engine in Python for the organization Swathanthra Malayalam	Core Developer
Computing.	
Programmatic creation of PDF books from HTML pages for non-latin scripts - A Python project	
to implement PDF exports of HTML content like wiki pages for non-latin scripts like all Indic	Developer
languages, Arabic etc.	
1	Socket.io to broker and render real time streaming data. Gdeploy - Developed a tool to set-up and deploy GlusterFS using ansible over multiple hosts. Wrote and maintained numerous Ansible modules for the upstream Ansible repository. Automated Rendering Testing - As a part of the Google Summer of Code project, wrote a tool to test the rendering of fonts by engine in Python for the organization Swathanthra Malayalam Computing. Programmatic creation of PDF books from HTML pages for non-latin scripts - A Python project to implement PDF exports of HTML content like wiki pages for non-latin scripts like all Indic

Other Achievements & Awards

	University of Cambridge sponsorship - The PeARS team was invited over to the University of
2016	Cambridge to be a part of the workshop series on Open source and NLP and to meet and work with
	the team face-to-face.
2014	Google Women Techmaker India - Was one among the 10 winners of Women Techmaker award
	given away by Google
2013	Linux foundation training scholarship - Won the Linux Foundation Training Scholarship awarded
	only to 5 people around the world under the category System Administration WhizKid
2013	Red Hat scholarship - Won a scholarship from Red Hat, where I was completely sponsored to
	attend the RHCSA training
	Google Summer of Code - Successfully implemented a framework in Python to automatically test
2013	the fonts rendered by engines as the Google Summer of Code project under the organization
	Swathanthra Malayalam Computing in the domain Natural Language Processing

Trainings & Certifications _____

2021	Certified Kubernetes Application Developer - Passed the CKAD certification by CNCF in July 2021. This exam certifies that candidates can design, build and deploy cloud-native applications for Kubernetes.	Remote
2017	Recurse Center - Got selected for a 3 month programmers' retreat in which computer science enthusiasts from all around the world participated and exchanged knowdledge	New York City
2013	Linux Foundation System Administration certification - Completed the Linux Foundation sys admin course	Remote
2013	Red Hat Certified System Administration course(RHCSA) - Completed RHCSA training covering advanced topics in system administration	Bangalore, India

Presentations & Talks _____

2016	Git internals and how to get involved in open source projects using it - University of Cambridge
2014	Open Source contributions - what and how? - College of Engineering, Munnar
2014	Deterministic parallel programming with Haskell - NSS College of Engineering, Palakkad, India
2012	Haira da fanta and this tasting. CMC 10th consequent Their control of

2013 **Unicode fonts and it's testing** - SMC 12th year event, Thrissur, India

2013 Introduction to Open Source Contributions - Devcon, Model Engineering College, India

2013 Swathanthra Malayalam Computing - An introduction - PMG HSS, PKD, India

2013 Free and Open Source software - An Introduction - Women's polytechnic college, Payyannur

2013 Rubygem packaging for Debian - FOSSMeet NIT Calicut, India

Education

Politecnico Di Milano Milano, Italy

 ${\tt MASTER}\ {\tt OF}\ {\tt Science} ({\tt Laurea}\ {\tt Magistrale})\ {\tt in}\ {\tt Computer}\ {\tt Science}\ {\tt and}\ {\tt Engineering}$

September 2017 - 2020

NSS College of Engineering (affiliated to the University of Calicut)

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Palakkad, India Mar. 2010 - April 2014

Technical Skills

Programming Languages - Golang, Python, Clojure, C, Ruby, Java, Elixir **Operating Systems** - GNU/Linux (Fedora, Debian and its derivatives, Arch Linux, & similar Linus distros)

 $\textbf{Languages} \ - \ \mathsf{Python}, \mathsf{Clojure}, \mathsf{Elixir}, \mathsf{C}, \mathsf{Ruby}, \mathsf{Go}(\mathsf{Basics}), \mathsf{HTML/CSS/Javascript}(\mathsf{working} \ \mathsf{knowledge}), \mathsf{Java}(\mathsf{basics})$

Infrastructure dev tools - Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform, AWS and GCP stacks, Ansible, OpenStack, MediaWiki, MySQL, Harfbuzz, LaTeX, Gimp, Scrapy, Twisted

Data management and processing - Different RDBMS and NoSQL flavours, Elasticsearch, Kafka, Spark, Flink, TinyOS